THE OPENING OF SAHASTRARA CHAKRA
فتح شاكرا الساهزترارا
5th MAY 1970, NARGOL (INDIA)
بتاريخ 5 آيار 1970، في نارغول (بالهند)
And it happened that I really saw the Sahastrara.
وحدث أنه حقا لقد شاهدت الساهزترارا.
(…) there’s a difference between your Sahastrara and Mine.
(...) هنالك فرق بين ساهزترارتكم وساهزترارتي.
And I saw the Sahastrara, which is big Sahastrara opened out beautifully.
ولقد رأيت الساهزترارا والتي هي ساهزترارا كبيرة، والتي انفتحت بشكل رائع.
And the petals were just like flames –
وأوراق زهرة (بتلة) الساهزترارا تبدو فعلا كالشعلات-
rounded flames, not like flames, but rounded ones,
شعلات مستديرة الشكل، لا تبدو كالشعلات العادية، بل مستديرة الشكل،
rounded beautifully coloured flames of different colours.
شعلات مستديرة ذو ألوان رائعة من مختلف الآلوان.
'Cause I saw so many permutations and combinations of these,
لأنني رأيت العديد جدا من التغيرات والتركيبات لهؤلائك،
so pronounced, so beautiful.
واضحة جدا، رائعة جدا.
And as if every petal was individually, absolutely complete and perfect,
وكأنه لو كانت كل بتلة (ورقة الزهرة) منفردة، ومتكاملة ومثالية كليا،
but so integrated to the base. And the way it opened out,
لكنها متحدة جدا عند القاعدة.  أما الطريقة التي فتحت بها،
and the movement was so rhythmic and so harmonious.
والحركة كانت كليا على الايقاع ومتناغمة جدا.
There was no problem. Such a harmony was between them.
لم يكن هنالك أية مشكلة. يا له من وئام وتناغنم بينهم.
No fluctuation anywhere,
لا تقلب ولا تغير في أي مكان،
as if they were dancing to the tunes, opened out.
كأنهم كانوا يرقصون على الايقاع الذي استرسل وانبعث.
And the colors, all spread out their light around with the auras,
ونشرت الألوان والهالات نورها في كل مكان حول،
and in the center I saw the Agnya, beaming in tear [?] and you can say the Sun color;
وفي الوسط رأيت الأغنيا (الشاكرا السادسة) تشع بالدمع [?]ويمكنكم القول انها كانت بلون الشمس،
and all the chakras were there, also emitting lights,
وكانت جميع الشكرات موجودة، تنبعث منها الأنوار أيضا،
but the chakras were darker in shades and they were emitting,
لكن الشكرات نفسها كانت داكنة اللون تحت الظل وكانت تبعث وتنشر(هذه الأنوار)،
so dark that they were all looking blackish, you see, so dark.
كانت غامقة جدا لدرجة انها كانت كلها تبدو مسودة اللون فعلا، داكنة جدا.
Sort of a condensed colour they had. And they were also emitting light all over.
كان للشكرات لون مكثف نوعا ما. وكان النور أيضا ينبعث في كل مكان.
And the light - as soon as the whole thing opened out, the light absolutely spread out.
والنور- منذ أن بدأ  كل شيء بالتفتح، امتد هذا النور كليا وانتشر.
And then I said: “It’s done. It can be done”.
وعندها قلت: "لقد تم. يمكنه أن يتم."
So first I had to open out My Sahastrara itself,
اذن أولا كان يجب أن أفتح  ساهزترارتي  نفسها،
then your Sahastraras could be opened out.
لتستطيعوا من بعدها أن تفتحوا  ساهزترارتكم.
And then I felt that a tremendous flow
ومن ثم شعرت بتدفق هائل
of My grace started flowing.
لنعمتي قد بدأت بالتدفق.
So much grace moving up on Me.
لقد امتلأت بقدر هائل من هذه النعمة من حولي.
My own principle [?] torrential rain, you see, falling on Me.
مبدئي الخاص  [?] فعلا كالمطر الغزير انهمر فوقي.
Absolutely I was so drenched in that joy, really I was lost, absolutely lost.
لقد انهمر فوقي  كم هائل من هذا الفرح بكل ما في الكلمة من معنى، فصرت كالتائهة والضائعة حقا، كليا زائغة ومبهورة.
Then I felt that the whole creation is now
ثم شعرت أن الخلق كله موجود الآن هنا
resounding with that Universal Consciousness, just felt that way.
يدوي مع هذا الوعي والادراك الكوني، هذا ما شعرت به تماما.
Everything was finished, only the joy of it was permeating.
كل شيء انتهى، فقط  بقي  الفرح بكل ذلك ما زال يتغلغل وينتشر.
The Sahastrara is the blessing of the heavens, I should say.
يمكنني القول أن الساهزترارا هي بركة من الفردوس.
It has worked out so well. It’s very difficult to break the Sahastrara.
لقد تحققت بنجاح كبير. انه لأمر صعب جدا فتح الساهزترارا.
And when I really broke it, I didn’t know that it would be that successful.
وعندما فتحتها حقا، لم أكن أدري أنها ستتوج يهذا القدر من النجاح.
First, I thought is still premature
أولا اعتقدت انها ما زالت سابقة لأوانها
because there are many Rakshasas still on the street, selling their goods;
لأنه ما زال هنالك العديد من الراكشاسا (الشرير) من حولنا في الشارع  يسوقون سلعهم ومتاعهم،
and there are many fanatics who are calling themselves by the so-called religions
وهنالك العديد من المتطرفين اللذين يدعون أنفسهم بما يسمى بالأديان
they are following, not the real religion of the Atma.
انهم لا يتبعون الدين الحقيقي الذي يمثل الروحانية.
But, gradually it has taken its roots. Now, let this truth
لكن تدريجيا تصبح  متجذرة. الآن دعوا هذه الحقيقة
take its root within yourself through your Sahastrara.
تتجذر بداخلكم من خلال ساهزترارتكم.
And once this truth becomes absolutely the light that guides you,
وعندما تصبح هذه الحقيقة كليا النور الذي يرشدكم،
the light that nourishes you, the light that enlightens you and gives you
النور الذي يغذيكم، النور الذي ينوركم ويعطيكم
a personality that has the light, then only you should know
شخصية منورة، عندها فقط يجب أن تعلموا
that your Sahastrara is completely enlightened by your Spirit.
أن ساهزترارتكم هي منورة كليا  عبر روحكم.
Your face should be such that people should know
يجب أن يكون وجهكم على هذا النحو بحيث يجب أن يعلم الناس
that there's a personality who’s standing before you who is light.
أن هنالك شخصية تقف أمامهم والتي هي منورة.
This is how Sahastrara is to be looked after.
هكذا يجب الاعتناء بالساهزترارا.
Please close your eyes.
من فضلكم أغمضوا عيونكم.
As it is, Kundalini has risen quite high. I feel it.
كما هي الكونداليني قد ارتفعت عاليا جدا،انني  أشعر بها.
But it has to cross through the last point, which is the seventh center
لكن يجب أن تعبر النقطة الأخيرة، التي هي المركز السابع
called as Sahastrara to pierce through the hole of -
الذي يطلق عليه اسم ساهزترارا حيث يتم خرمه عبر فتحة-
is called as the Brahma, is the Brahmarandhra
تدعى البراهما، وهو البراهمارندهرا
where you get your Baptism, the real Baptism, actualizing it.
حيث تحصلوا على معموديتكم، العمادة الحقيقية، لقد تم تحقيقها حقا.
Please close your eyes.
الرجاء غمض اعينكم.
Just don't open your eyes.
فقط لا تفتحوا أعينكم.
That's very important part of Sahaj Yoga that you don't open your eyes.
انه لجزء هام جدا في الساهاجا يوغا أن لا تفتحوا أعينكم.
Because, if you open your eyes,
لأنه اذا فتحتم أعينكم،
then the Kundalini doesn't rise above the Agnya chakra which is the sixth center.
عندها لن ترتفع الكونداليني فوق الأغنيا شاكرا الذي هو المركز السادس.
Put your right hand on your heart. Don't open your eyes, please,
ضعوا يدكم اليمنى على قلبكم. لا تفتحو أعينكم، من فضلكم،
but put your right hand on your heart. Then ask a question -
لكن ضعوا يدكم اليمنى على قلبكم. ثم اسألوا هذا السؤال-
for those who have not yet got their Realization fully established -
للذين لم يثبتوا بعد التحقيق الذاتي الكلي-
ask a question, "Mother, am I the Spirit?".
اسألوا هذا السؤال، "أمي (الكونداليني)، هل أنا الروح؟"
And the Sahaj Yogis have to say, "Mother, I’m the Spirit."
والساهاجا يوغي عليهم أن يسألوا: "أمي، أنا الروح."
In your heart. You need not say loudly. Thrice.
بداخل قلبكم. لستم بحاجة أن تقولوا ذلك بصوت عال، 3 مرات
Put your left hand on top of your head.
ضعوا يدكم اليسرى على اعلى رأسكم.
Are you feeling? Little... not touching it,
هل تشعرون؟ قليلا... لا تلمسوا رأسكم،
keep it higher, higher, still higher, on the place
ضعوها أعلى، أعلى، أعلى بعد أكثر، بالمكان (فوق النافوخ)
where we call it as a taloo, where the fontanel bone area,
حيث ندعوه تالوو، حيث موقع عظمة النافوخ،
where it was soft when you were a child.
حيث كانت طرية عندما كنتم أطفالا.
Bring it nearer to the head and see if you are feeling the Cool Breeze coming out.
ضعوها أقرب نحو الرأس ولاحظوا اذا كنتم تشعرون بخروج النسيم العليل فوق رأسكم.
May God bless you.
ليبارككم الله.